

+ (852) 62157045 | dilin7-c@my.cityu.edu.hk | GitHub | Blog | Kaggle

SUMMARY

With four years of experience in Java development, I am well-versed in various mainstream Java frameworks and middleware. Proficient in Java and Python for backend development, I also possess frontend development skills and Ops experience. I have a strong command of Hadoop and Spark for parallel computing, allowing me to effectively process and analyze large-scale data. My graduate studies focus on data science and machine learning, where I am familiar with popular frameworks like PyTorch and TensorFlow, having extensive practical experience in deep learning and NLP projects.

EDUCATION

City University of Hong Kong

Sept 2022 - Jun 2024 (Expected)

MSC in Computer Science

Wuhan University

Sept 2014 - Jun 2018

B.Eng. in Information Security

Wuhan, China

Bachelor of Economics (Minor)

WORK EXPERIENCE

China Merchants Financial Technology Co., Ltd.

Jul 2018 - Jun 2022

Java Developer (2018-2022) & Team Technical Head (2020-2022)

Shenzhen, China

- Developed and maintained multiple critical platforms and systems, including CM Worklink, Group Legal
 Compliance System, Digital Financial Services Platform etc.
- Proficient in Java and Python for backend development, with frontend development skills. Experienced in using frameworks and libraries like Vue.js, ElementUI, jQuery, and Layui.
- Strong knowledge of Java development frameworks such as Spring, Spring Boot, Mybatis, and Hibernate. Familiar with Java middleware like Kafka, RabbitMQ, Tomcat, Jetty, Netty, and Nginx.
- Proficient in relational databases like MySQL and Oracle, with SQL optimization experience. Familiar with NoSQL databases like MongoDB, Redis, and Elasticsearch.
- Skilled in Hadoop and Spark for big data processing and parallel computing.
- Led architectural design and changes for various systems in the financial technology domain.
- Responsible for technology selection, as well as some system operations and maintenance tasks.
- Established coding standards for the team and organized regular code reviews.

HONORS AND AWARDS

Multiple Heisters Miner Class C Calcalantin (ten 45% students)	2017
Wuhan University: Minor Class C Scholarship (top 15% students)	2017
Wuhan University: Minor Class A Scholarship (top 5% students)	2016
Wuhan University: Excellent Student (top 25% students)	2016
Wuhan University: Class C Scholarship (top 25% students)	2016

PATENTS

(1) Jing LIAO, Xun LI, Rizhen WEI, **Di LIN**, Jing Zhang, Zhancheng Xie, Guochao Zhong, (2020). Data association and inspection method and device, electronic equipment and storage medium. (CN112445875A)

SKILLS

Languages | C/C++, Java, Python, Scala

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Di LIN, Pengzhen XIAO, (2023). An LSTM-Based Model for LLM Generated Text Detection

- Implemented an LTSM-based model for LLM text identification, including embedding layer, LSTM layer, fully connected layer, and other layers.
- The process included data preprocessing, feature extraction, clustering, dimension reduction, model optimization and other steps.
- Model optimization approaches including using pre-trained models, data augmentation, network architecture optimization, hyperparameter tuning, dropout, and word embeddings.

Di LIN, Runlin HOU, Zhehao JIN, Jianhua HUANG, (2023). A CNN-Based Model for Sign Language Recognition

- Tried various linear classifiers and non-linear classifiers to fit data better, finally chose to implement a CNN-based model for sign language recognition.
- Model optimization approaches including data augmentation, network architecture optimization, dropout, learning rate scheduling, and random search for faster hyperparameter optimization. Finally, the test accuracy promoted to 0.890.
- Evaluation based on accuracy, precision, recall, and confusion matrix, indicating the primary error is that 'R', 'K', and 'Y' were all classified to 'R'.

Zhen SUN, Di LIN, Peiyuan GUO, (2022). A DenseNet-Based Model for Bird Classification

- Implemented a DenseNet-based model for bird classification, including multiple dense blocks, transition layers and pooling layers.
- Model optimization approaches including data augmentation, ImageNet pre-training, DenseNet architecture optimization, and adding Squeeze-and-Excitation Networks.
- Finally, the test accuracy promoted to 0.862 which ImageNet pre-training contributed most. The model achieved a significant improvement than baseline ResNet model.

Di LIN, Peiling LIU, (2022). Generator-GUI: A Convenient Java Code Generator

- The Java code generator was implemented to replace those repetitive and tedious code work in Java
 application developing, which could auto generate controller, service, DTO and mapper codes according to
 chosen database tables and configuration.
- GUI was implemented for convenience. Users can integrate it into the IDE or use it independently outside the IDE.
- Suitable for mainstream Java frameworks, including Spring, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, etc.